<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on a rant of my adventures</title><link>https://blog.caprinux.com/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on a rant of my adventures</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.caprinux.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Reversing a Playstation X Application?</title><link>https://blog.caprinux.com/posts/ctfs/2023/wgmy2023/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.caprinux.com/posts/ctfs/2023/wgmy2023/</guid><description>WGMY 2024 &amp;ndash; RmRf &amp;ldquo;What happened to my system? It has been working perfectly for more than 20 years.&amp;rdquo;
We are given a zip that contains a bin and cue file. If we run strings, we see that it points to a playstation/PSX program.
I extracted the ISO file by running binwalk --extract rmrf.bin. From the ISO file, we can extract the playstation EXE by using unar.
rmrf &amp;gt; binwalk --extract rmrf.</description></item><item><title>Blahaj CTF Pwn Writeups</title><link>https://blog.caprinux.com/posts/ctfs/2023/blahaj-ctf/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.caprinux.com/posts/ctfs/2023/blahaj-ctf/</guid><description>Blahaj CTF was an entry-level CTF that was targeted at secondary school and JC students in Singapore. Having not touched pwn for awhile, the pwn challenges were fun, refreshing and even challenging. There were a total of 4 pwn challenges, 3 simpler ones and 1 challenging one. The writeups for the 4 challenges are below and in increasing difficulty.
This writeup aims to be dummy-friendly, and a good guide for absolute beginners to learn binary exploitation.</description></item><item><title>Life Update -- new blog!</title><link>https://blog.caprinux.com/posts/ctfs/2023/life-update/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.caprinux.com/posts/ctfs/2023/life-update/</guid><description>hey, to whoever reads this, it&amp;rsquo;s been awhile :&amp;quot;) how&amp;rsquo;s life?
for myself, life has been absolutely shitty recently &amp;#x1f912; i&amp;rsquo;m currently going through alot, and i&amp;rsquo;m currently finding ways to cope with things &amp;ndash; exploring and occupying myself with new stuff
it&amp;rsquo;s been over a year since i have last updated my blog (not sure if anyone reads it but whatever 🤭), and i&amp;rsquo;ve modified the entire website (yay dark mode!</description></item><item><title>Window of Opportunity -- Intro to Kernel Exploitation</title><link>https://blog.caprinux.com/posts/ctfs/2023/ictf-window-of-opportunity/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2023 05:59:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.caprinux.com/posts/ctfs/2023/ictf-window-of-opportunity/</guid><description>Imaginary CTF 2023 has just ended and it once again did not disappoint. The CTF featured a variety of fun and interesting challenges. Kudos to the organizers for yet another successful event.
One of the interesting challenges that I solved this year was window-of-opportunity, which is a kernelspace pwn challenge. In this writeup, I will share my thought processes and hopefully bring you some insights or new knowledge into the world of kernelspace!</description></item><item><title>SEETF 2023 Pwn Writeups</title><link>https://blog.caprinux.com/posts/ctfs/2023/seetf2023-pwns/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2023 05:59:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.caprinux.com/posts/ctfs/2023/seetf2023-pwns/</guid><description>SEETF Brief Writeup on Pwns Shellcode As A Service As indicated by the challenge name and description, we have to write shellcode that will be executed by the program.
We are given an initial write of 6 bytes long, which allows us to get a second stage write. There is open, read seccomp, preventing us from printing flag.
We can write a loop in assembly to read one character at a time, and terminate if the character is incorrect.</description></item><item><title>Weapon Safety -- Windows Pwn</title><link>https://blog.caprinux.com/posts/ctfs/2022/cyberleague-weapon-safety/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2023 05:59:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.caprinux.com/posts/ctfs/2022/cyberleague-weapon-safety/</guid><description>Weapon Safety Initial Analysis We are provided with a 64-bit windows executable. If we throw it into IDA, we can see that it did not manage to find the main function.
However we have the _start function and we can easily find this main function ourselves by either looking for strings in the program and finding cross references
or clicking into the start function and finding the main function (somewhere in the last block), which can be identified by the function call right after 3 arguments are being loaded (r8, rdx, ecx).</description></item><item><title>Flag Checker (pwn) -- War Games Malaysia</title><link>https://blog.caprinux.com/posts/ctfs/2022/wgmy-flag-checker/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2022 05:59:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.caprinux.com/posts/ctfs/2022/wgmy-flag-checker/</guid><description>FlagChecker pwn challenge from wgmy2022
FlagChecker.zip ├── bin │ ├── flag_checker │ └── flag.txt ├── ctf.xinetd ├── docker-compose.yml ├── Dockerfile └── start.sh Setup Since we are provided with the Dockerfile, we can start by setting up our environment (extracting the LIBC and LD) to mimic the environment of the server.
Upon setting up our docker, we can spawn a shell as shown below
❯ docker exec -it wgmy-flag_checker-1 /bin/bash root@ef917d02df99:/home/ctf# ldd flag_checker # show the dependencies linux-vdso.</description></item><item><title>TISC 2022</title><link>https://blog.caprinux.com/posts/ctfs/2022/tisc-2022/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.caprinux.com/posts/ctfs/2022/tisc-2022/</guid><description>The Challenge The Information Security Challenge (TISC) is an annual Capture The Flag (CTF) competition hosted by the Centre for Strategic Infocomm Technologies (CSIT) in Singapore.
The CTF features a series of 10 levels over the span of 2 weeks, covering various CTF topics including, but not limited to, Web Pen-testing, Forensics, Reverse Engineering, Binary Exploitation, Cryptography, and Mobile Security.
In order to unlock levels, you had to clear all the levels before.</description></item><item><title>Imaginary CTF 2022 Writeups</title><link>https://blog.caprinux.com/posts/ctfs/2022/imaginaryctf-2022/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.caprinux.com/posts/ctfs/2022/imaginaryctf-2022/</guid><description>Currently serving conscription. These are writeups of challenges that I solved on a tablet from my army camp 👍👍
ret2win (100 pts) - 266 solves Jumping around in memory is hard. I&amp;rsquo;ll give you some help so that you can pwn this! Author: Eth007
vuln vuln.c
Analysis #include &amp;lt;stdio.h&amp;gt; #include &amp;lt;stdlib.h&amp;gt; int win() { FILE *fp; char flag[255]; fp = fopen(&amp;#34;flag.txt&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;r&amp;#34;); fgets(flag, 255, fp); puts(flag); } char **return_address; int main() { char buf[16]; return_address = buf+24; setvbuf(stdout,NULL,2,0); setvbuf(stdin,NULL,2,0); puts(&amp;#34;Welcome to ret2win!</description></item><item><title>Miscellaneous CTF Writeups</title><link>https://blog.caprinux.com/posts/ctfs/2022/miscellaneous-ctf-writeups/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2022 05:59:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.caprinux.com/posts/ctfs/2022/miscellaneous-ctf-writeups/</guid><description>redirecting you to my old ctf-writeup github repository in 1 second</description></item><item><title>dCTF - cache (pwn)</title><link>https://blog.caprinux.com/posts/ctfs/2022/dctf-cache/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.caprinux.com/posts/ctfs/2022/dctf-cache/</guid><description>After many lazy months and a long hiatus, I finally found some time to sit down and see through a slightly less than trivial pwn challenge.
Competed under the team xiao zhu zhus alongside my other xiao zhu zhu in the team.
Overview Can you catch me?
Flag format: CTF{sha256}
Files: vuln.zip
Trivial Preview Right off the bat, we are provided with the vulnerable program vuln as well as the libc used for this program in the remote server.</description></item><item><title>zh3ro CTF - more printf (pwn)</title><link>https://blog.caprinux.com/posts/ctfs/2021/zh3ro-more-printf/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.caprinux.com/posts/ctfs/2021/zh3ro-more-printf/</guid><description>Challenge Description printf();
nc pwn.zh3r0.cf 2222
Attached: printf.tar.gz
Author - hk
Overview Extracting the tar archive, we are provided with a binary, the source code, and libc-2.27.so.
/* gcc -o more-printf -fstack-protector-all more-printf.c */ #include &amp;lt;stdint.h&amp;gt; #include &amp;lt;stdio.h&amp;gt; #include &amp;lt;stdlib.h&amp;gt; #include &amp;lt;unistd.h&amp;gt; FILE *fp; char *buffer; uint64_t i = 0x8d9e7e558877; _Noreturn main() { /* Just to save some of your time */ uint64_t *p; p = &amp;amp;p; /* Chall */ setbuf(stdin, 0); buffer = (char *)malloc(0x20 + 1); fp = fopen(&amp;#34;/dev/null&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;wb&amp;#34;); fgets(buffer, 0x1f, stdin); if (i !</description></item><item><title>ictf - A little birdie once told me... (pwn)</title><link>https://blog.caprinux.com/posts/ctfs/2021/ictf-birdie/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.caprinux.com/posts/ctfs/2021/ictf-birdie/</guid><description>I thought this was a good challenge so I decided to do a writeup on it. This challenge was from ictf 2021 May batch of challenges.
ictf is a discord server to get daily CTF (Capture the Flag) challenges aimed mostly towards beginners (with occasional difficult challenges). Moreover, no sign-up is required, everything is on discord.
Overview If at first you don&amp;rsquo;t succeed, try try again&amp;hellip; Connect with nc 140.238.222.141 42000.</description></item><item><title>dCTF - Formats Last Theorem(pwn)</title><link>https://blog.caprinux.com/posts/ctfs/2021/dctf-formats-last-theorem/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.caprinux.com/posts/ctfs/2021/dctf-formats-last-theorem/</guid><description>Challenge Description I dare you to hook the malloc
nc dctf-chall-formats-last-theorem.westeurope.azurecontainer.io 7482
formats_last_theorem Dockerfile
Overview We are provided with the binary and a docker file. We first check the security features of the binary.
[*] &amp;apos;/media/sf_dabian/Challenges/dctf/pwn/lft/formats_last_theorem&amp;apos; Arch: amd64-64-little RELRO: Full RELRO Stack: No canary found NX: NX enabled PIE: PIE enabled Connecting to the service, we get prompted for an input, which seems to continuously loop and prompt for more input.</description></item><item><title>dCTF - Hotel ROP (pwn)</title><link>https://blog.caprinux.com/posts/ctfs/2021/dctf-hotel-rop/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.caprinux.com/posts/ctfs/2021/dctf-hotel-rop/</guid><description>This writeup will be more PwnTools-oriented since this writeup will also be cross-posted onto Pwntools Blog.
Today, we will be looking at a pwn challenge from dCTF 2021 which features ret2libc exploitation with a little twist of a PIE-enabled binary. The following PwnTools features will be introduced here:
pwnlib.rop to help us craft ROP chains pwnlib.elf to make finding addresses quick and easy and many more little modules from pwntools to help us pwn faster ~ Challenge Description They say programmers&amp;rsquo; dream is California.</description></item><item><title>3kCTF - MasterC (pwn)</title><link>https://blog.caprinux.com/posts/ctfs/2021/3kctf-masterc/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.caprinux.com/posts/ctfs/2021/3kctf-masterc/</guid><description>Threaded win? is that even a thing?
nc masterc.2021.3k.ctf.to 9999
Attachment: masterc.tgz
Overview We are provided with the libc, ld, source code and the binary itself.
Running checksec on the binary, we see all security features green
[*] &amp;#39;/media/sf_dabian/Challenges/3kctf/masterc/masterc/bin/masterc&amp;#39; Arch: amd64-64-little RELRO: Full RELRO Stack: Canary found NX: NX enabled PIE: PIE enabled Enter the size : Enter the number of tries : Enter your guess : We are prompted with 3 inputs upon running the binary.</description></item><item><title>Cyberthon 2021 - APCafe (pwn)</title><link>https://blog.caprinux.com/posts/ctfs/2021/cyberthon-apcafe/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 05:59:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.caprinux.com/posts/ctfs/2021/cyberthon-apcafe/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;ve received intel that APOCALYPSE is running a cafe as a front for their illegal activities. Although it seems like a regular cafe on the outside, serving local favourites such as Kopi-O, Milo, and Yuan Yang, we believe that something more sinister is going on. Could u try to find a way to break in so we can investigate further?
Interact with the service at: aiodmb3uswokssp2pp7eum8qwcsdf52r.ctf.sg:30101
Note: once you get a shell, the flag.</description></item><item><title>Cyberthon 2021 - APCDB (pwn)</title><link>https://blog.caprinux.com/posts/ctfs/2021/cyberthon-apcdb/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 05:59:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.caprinux.com/posts/ctfs/2021/cyberthon-apcdb/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;ve found a network service that seems to be posing as a fake directory of APOCALYPSE members. Although it doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to be hooked up to any actual database, it does look a tad vulnerable. Could u try to break in anyway? Who knows, access to this server might come in useful.
Interact with the service at: aiodmb3uswokssp2pp7eum8qwcsdf52r.ctf.sg:30201
Note: once you get a shell, the flag.txt can be found in the user&amp;rsquo;s home directory.</description></item><item><title>Cyberthon 2021 - PlaceHolder (pwn)</title><link>https://blog.caprinux.com/posts/ctfs/2021/cyberthon-placeholder/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 05:59:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.caprinux.com/posts/ctfs/2021/cyberthon-placeholder/</guid><description>Hohoho seems like one of the APOCALYPSE agents messed up big time. Seems this agent went to deploy his/her code for testing and completely forgot to bring down the network service. This careless agent even forgot to private the repository containing the test code, so we&amp;rsquo;ve managed to obtain the source for the entire project, dockerfile and all. We&amp;rsquo;ve provided you with everything that we&amp;rsquo;ve found, so can you get the flag from their server?</description></item></channel></rss>